For loops are an example of definite iteration
for 循环是一种有限迭代
meaning that the loop's body is run a predefined number of times.
即循环主体的运行次数已提前定义好
A for loop over a list executes the body once for each element in the list.
列表 for 循环会针对列表中的每个元素运行主体一次
A for loop using the range function will
使用函数 range() 的 for 循环
execute the number of times specified by the range function.
执行次数将由函数 range() 指定
This differs from indefinite iteration,
这与无限迭代不同
which is when a loop repeats an unknown number of times,
即循环重复次数不定
and ends when some condition is met.
当满足某个条件时 循环结束
Consider this while loop that simulates a blackjack dealer by drawing cards from
看看这个 while 循环示例 该循环模拟的是一个二十一点庄家
a deck list into a hand list stopping when
庄家会从一副牌中抽取纸牌放入玩家手中
the value of the cards in the hand is 17 or more.
当玩家手中的牌点数之和是 17 点或更多时 停止抽牌
This example features a new function,
这个示例用到了一个新的函数 sum()
"sum," and a new list method, "pop."
和一个新的列表方法 pop()
Sum is pretty intuitive.
sum() 很好理解
It returns the sum of the elements in a list.
它返回的是列表中的元素之和
Pop is the inverse of the append method.
pop() 是方法 append() 的对立面
It removes the last element from a list and returns it.
它从列表中删除最后一个元素并返回该元素
You can read more about this in the official documentation.
你可以在官方文档中了解更多详情
In this line, we are computing the sum of
这行代码的目的是计算列表 hand 中的元素之和
the list hand and checking if that is less than or equal to 17.
并检查和是否小于或等于 17
In this line, we are popping the last element from
在这一行 我们从 card_deck 中拿出最后一个元素
card_deck and appending that to the hand list.
并将其附加到列表 hand 中
Let's talk about how this while loop works.
我们看看这个 while 循环的原理
The while keyword indicates that this is a while loop.
关键字 while 表示这是一个 while 循环
Next is the condition.
接下来是条件
In this example, sum(hand) is less than or equal to 17.
在此示例中 条件是 sum(hand) &lt;= 17
If this condition is true,
如果该条件为 true
the loop's body will be executed.
则执行循环的主体部分
Each time the loop's body runs,
每次运行循环的主体时
the condition is evaluated again.
都再次检查该条件
This process of checking the condition and then running
这一检查条件然后运行循环的流程会不断重复
the loop repeats until the expression becomes false.
直到该表达式变成 false
The indented body of the loop should modify at least one variable in the test expression.
循环的缩进主体部分应该至少修改测试表达式中的一个变量
If the value of the test expression never changes,
如果测试表达式的值始终不变
the result is an infinite loop.
循环将变成无限循环
In this example, the loop's body appends numbers to the hand list,
在此示例中 循环的主体会向列表 hand 中附加数字
which increases the value of sum(hand).
这样就会增加 sum(hand) 的值
Eventually, the value of sum(hand) becomes large enough that the condition becomes false.
最终 sum(hand) 的值将变得足够大 使该条件变成 false